Harshal Girish Narkhede

m www.harshalnarkhede.com

(+91) 9664293463

github.com/hgnarkhede

Linked in

SUMMARY

3+ years experienced AWS Solutions Architect of client-facing experience with a prolific track record in Solutions Design for Cloud technologies to formulate and execute high-growth strategies across a wide spectrum of domains. Cognitive about designing, deploying and operating highly available, scalable and fault tolerant systems on cloud.

EXPERIENCE

Cloud Data Analyst @ Accenture

October 2017 - Present | Mumbai, IN

Claims Analytics and Visualization in Insurance Industry

April 2020 - Present | Global Insurance Analytics | Connecticut, USA

- Perform predictive analytics using customer claims data to identify potential outliers that eventually develop into high value losses.
- Architected and embedded visualization dashboard of claims, policy data in an Angular application by utilizing QuickSight's serverless architecture to easily scale out the insights with the growing user base
- ▶ Create CloudFormation template to facilitate automated deployment of the resources
- Used IAM for creating roles, users, groups and attached policies to provide minimum access to the resources
- Environment: AWS Cloud, Technology: IAM, QuickSight, Glue, Cognito, STS, CloudFormation, ELB, Security Groups, CloudFront, STS, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, VPC, EC2

Data Solutions Architect in Food Service Industry

Feb 2019 - March 2020 | Data Governance Team | Chicago, USA

- Successfully ported a legacy, on-premises application to AWS and achieved significant increase in availability
- Select, provision and monitor appropriate AWS service based on data, compute, database and security requirements
- Analyzed client requirements and determined system architecture to achieve business goals
- ▶ Experienced interactions with senior management executives and across functional areas
- Environment: AWS Cloud Technology: IAM, VPC, EC2, SES, SNS, CloudFront, S3, ELB, Lambda, API Gateway, EMR, CloudWatch

IOT Analytics in Oil and Gas Industry

May 2018 - Jan 2019 | Global Enterprise Analytics | Singapore

- ▶ Manage large volume of sensor data and combine with right decision logic to trigger actions
- ▶ Collect and store streaming data at any scale and at low cost
- Analyze streaming data running on the edge to identify behavior patterns and event detection
- ▶ Visualize live and historical equipment data using QuickSight
- Environment: AWS Cloud Technology: IOT SiteWise, IoT Greengrass, IoT Core, IOT Analytics, IOT Events, IAM, SNS, SES, Lambda, S3, Kinesis, QuickSight

Data Analytics for Wine and Spirits Distributor

Oct 2017 - May 2018 | Data Analytics Team | Florida, USA

- Perform predictive analytics on customers legacy data to predict key performance metrics using time series modeling
- Connect legacy data stored in S3 to notebook instances and transform data to gather meaningful insights by utilizing NumPy and Pandas library in PySpark
- ▶ Learning new tools and skillsets as needs arise.
- ▶ Environment: AWS Cloud Technology: PySpark, SageMaker, S3, IAM, NumPy, Pandas

SKILLS

Cloud

Amazon AWS (Computing Services, Storage Services, Networking & Content Delivery, Developer Tools, Containers, Machine Learning, Database Services, Security and Identity Services)

Machine Learning Algorithms

XGBoost, Reinforcement Learning, Forecasting, Text Analysis, Ensemble Learning, Regression

Languages

PySpark, SQL, HTML, CSS

Data Analytics Skills

Data Visualization, Data Cleaning, Feature Selection, Pandas

Operating Systems

Mac, Windows and Linux

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

June 2020 | Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified Developer Associate

Sep 2020 | Amazon Web Services

Certified Cloud Data Engineer

Oct 2020 | Accenture

EDUCATION

MIT

2013 - 2017 | Pune

Bachelor of Electronics and Telecommunications IEEE Student Branch Chairman

LEADERSHIP

Nonprofit Digital Transformation Manager

2019 - 2020 | Mumbai

Spearheaded a team of 3 developers, content creators and a legal advisor to assess 15+ proposals and to initiate application deployment on cloud

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

ACE Award - FY20 Q2 May 2020 | Accenture

INTERESTS

Golf, Travel, Music and Life